Guide to the Centerbrook Architects and Planners Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Project records, Circa 1963-2004
  - Springfield Crafts Village, 1980
    - Negatives (Box E38)
  - Stanwood House, 1979
    Job location: Bloomfield, CT
    - Manuscript Materials (Box D5)
    - Sketches (Box D5, Box D32)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box D31, Box D33)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box D30, Box D33, Box D40)
    - Mechanical/Electrical/HVAC Drawings (Box D30)
    - Photographs (Box D5)
    - Slides (Box D5)
  - Stern House, 1971
    - Manuscript Materials (Box M1)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box M11)
    - Slides (Box M1)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box M11)
  - Stern Toole & Shaw Office, 1981
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box M12)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box M12)
  - Striar Jewish Community Center, 1988
    - Manuscript Materials (Box J49–J57)
    - Sketches (Box J39–J40)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box J37–J40)
    - Landscape/Site Drawings (Box J46–J48)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box J1, Box J58)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box J41–J48)
    - Mechanical/Electrical/HVAC Drawings (Box J41–J48)
    - Photographs (Box J57)
    - Slides (Box J57)
  - Swan House, 1975-1976
    Job location: Southhold, NY
    - Manuscript Materials (Box C6)
    - Sketches (Box C10)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box C9, Box C11–C13)
    - Photographs (Box C6)
    - Slides (Box C6)
  - Swanson House I, II, 1976; 1983
    Job location: Chicago; Cherry Hills, IL, CO
    - Sketches (Box D12–D13)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box D12)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box D14)
    - Negatives (Box E55)
  - Talbert House, 1965
    Job location: Oakland, CA
    - Manuscript Materials (Box N3)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box N3)
    - Photographs (Box N3)
  - Taplin House, 1981
    Job location: Amesbury, MA
    - Manuscript Materials (Box E38)
    - Sketches (Box E60)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box E60)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box E60)
    - Photographs (Box E38)
    - Slides (Box E38)
  - Taylor Town Houses, 1972
    Job location: Norwalk, CT
    - Manuscript Materials (Box F27)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box F65)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box F59, Box F64)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box F65)
    - Photographs (Box F27)
  - Taylor-Walker Residence, 1990-1991
    - Manuscript Materials (Box P199–P200)
    - Sketches (Box P194)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box P195–P198)
    - Landscape/Site Drawings (Box P162)
  - Tempchin House, 1968-1969
    Job location: Bethesda, MD
    - Manuscript Materials (Box B60)
    - Sketches (Box B64)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box B63–B64)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box B64)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box B63)
    - Photographs (Box B60)
    - Slides (Box B60)
    - Negatives (Box B60)
  - Tortilla City Hall (student project), 1956
    Job location: Tortilla, CA
    - Manuscript Materials (Box N3)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box N3)
  - Tower East, 1982
    - Manuscript Materials (Box C5)
    - Sketches (Box C28, Box C31)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box K6, Box C28, Box C30, Box C32, Box C36)
    - Landscape/Site Drawings (Box C30, Box C32–C33)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box K6, Box C28–C29)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box C27, Box C29, Box C33)
    - Mechanical/Electrical/HVAC Drawings (Box C34–C35)
    - Photographs (Box C2, Box C5)
    - Slides (Box C5)
    - Negatives (Box I1)
  - Tower One, 1967-1970
    - Manuscript Materials (Box C3)
    - Sketches (Box C22)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box C21–C23)
    - Landscape/Site Drawings (Box C23)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box C22)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box C24, Box C26–C27)
    - Negatives (Reel C4)
  - Tri-Pac Housing, 1968
    Job location: Vernon, CT
    - Manuscript Materials (Box B60)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box B65)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box B60, Box B65)
    - Photographs (Box B60)
    - Negatives (Box B60)
  - University of California Arts Center Competition, 1966
    Job location: California
    - Manuscript Materials (Box N3)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box N3)
    - Photographs (Box N3)
  - University of California, Santa Barbara: Faculty Club, 1966-1968
    - Manuscript Materials (Box A22)
    - Presentation Drawings (Folder A16)
    - Photographs (Box C2, Box C54, Folder A28)
    - Negatives (Box E55)
  - University of California, Santa Cruz: Kresge College, 1966-1974
    - Manuscript Materials (Box C3, Box A24, Box B60)
    - Sketches (Folder A3)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Folder A1–A2, Folder A5–A6)
    - Landscape/Site Drawings (Box A21, Folder A5)
    - Presentation Drawings (Folder A4)
    - Photographs (Box C2)
    - Slides (Box A24)
    - Negatives (Box A27, Box E55)
  - University of Connecticut Staff Housing, 1968
    Job location: Storrs, CT
    - Manuscript Materials (Box B60)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box B66)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box N13, Box B66)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box B66)
    - Photographs (Box B60)
    - Slides (Box B60)
    - Negatives (Box E55, Box B60)
  - University of Toledo, Honors Housing and Academic Center, 1993
    Job location: Toledo, OH
    - Manuscript Materials (Box Q13–Q14)
    - Sketches (Box Q43–Q44)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box Q40, Box Q43–Q44)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box Q36)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box Q41)
    - Mechanical/Electrical/HVAC Drawings (Box Q42)
    - Photographs (Box Q14)
  - Villa del Monte, 1969
    Job location: Seaside, CA
    - Manuscript Materials (Box C3, Box B71)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box B67)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box C37)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box B67)
    - Photographs (Box B71)
    - Slides (Box B71)
  - Wallingford Rail Station - Yale Student Project
    Job location: Wallingford, CT
    - Presentation Drawings (Box N2)
  - Washburn Houses, 1966
    Job location: Pacific Grove, CA
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box B68)
  - Watkins Glen Development Plan ["Watkins Glen Tomorrow"], 1979
    Job location: Watkins Glen, NY
    - Manuscript Materials (Box J2, Box S59)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box J59)
    - Landscape/Site Drawings (Box S59)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box J6)
    - Photographs (Box J2)
    - Slides (Box J2)
    - Negatives (Box J2, Box J59)
    - Audiovisual Materials (Box J2)
  - Watkins Glen Marina, 1984
    - Manuscript Materials (Box K4)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box K47)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box K47)
    - Photographs (Box K4)
    - Slides (Box K4)
  - Watkins Glen Pier and Pavilion, 1984
    - Manuscript Materials (Box K4)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box K48)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box K48)
    - Slides (Box K4)
  - Watkins Glen Seneca Market, 1984
    - Manuscript Materials (Box K4)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box K49)
    - Photographs (Box K4)
    - Slides (Box K4)
  - Watkins Glen State Park, including Timespell, 1985
    - Manuscript Materials (Box K4)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box K50)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box K47)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box K50)
    - Mechanical/Electrical/HVAC Drawings (Box K50)
    - Slides (Box K4)
    - Negatives (Box K4)
  - Weltner House and Pottery Studio, 1973
    Job location: Haddam, CT
    - Manuscript Materials (Box N2)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box D19)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box D19)
    - Photographs (Box N2)
  - Wernick Offices, 1980
    Job location: Bristol, CT
    - Sketches (Box E62–E63)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box E61)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box E38, Box E62–E63)
    - Slides (Box E38)
    - Negatives (Box E38)
  - West Plaza Condominiums, 1962
    Job location: Coronado, CA
    - Manuscript Materials (Box N4)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box N4)
    - Photographs (Box N4)
  - Weyerhauser Demonstration House, 1968-1969
    - Manuscript Materials (Box N2)
    - Photographs (Box N2)
  - Whitman Village, 1971-1975
    - Manuscript Materials (Box N1, Box B71)
    - Landscape/Site Drawings (Box B69)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box B72)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box B69–B70)
    - Photographs (Box N1, Box C2, Box B71)
    - Slides (Box B71)
    - Negatives (Box B72)
  - Williams College Museum of Art: Phase I, 1983
    - Manuscript Materials (Box I4, Box I10–I11)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box I5–I6, Box R29)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box I1, Box I4)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box I7–I9)
    - Mechanical/Electrical/HVAC Drawings (Box I9)
    - Photographs (Box I4)
    - Slides (Box I4)
    - Negatives (Box I4)
  - Williams College Museum of Art: Phase II, 1986
    - Manuscript Materials (Box I4, Box I16–I19)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box I13)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box I1, Box I5)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box I12, Box I14–I15)
    - Photographs (Box I4)
    - Slides (Box I4)
    - Negatives (Box I4)
  - Williams College: Charles Moore Exhibit, 1989
    - Presentation Drawings (Box E55)
    - Photographs (Box E55)
  - Wolfe [Robert T.] Housing for the Elderly, 1968-1970
    - Manuscript Materials (Box B71)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box B74)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box I2, Box B75)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box B73)
    - Photographs (Box B71, Reel C4)
    - Slides (Box B71)
    - Negatives (Box B71)
  - Wooster Street Housing Redevelopment Project B-19, 1968
    - Presentation Drawings (Box C55, Box E84)
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box C58)
    - Photographs (Box C2, Box C5)
    - Slides (Box C5)
    - Negatives (Box C2, Box E55)
  - Worcester Polytechnic Insitute Campus Plan, 1970
    Job location: Worcester, MA
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box C60–C61)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box C7–C8)
    - Photographs (Box C5)
    - Slides (Box C5)
    - Negatives (Box C2, Box C5)
  - Wrexham Hall, 1970
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box C52)
    - Mechanical/Electrical/HVAC Drawings (Box C52)
  - Xanadune, 1972
    Job location: St. Simon Island, GA
    - Manuscript Materials (Box C5)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box K6, Box C50–C51)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box I1, Box K6, Box E85)
    - Photographs (Box C5)
    - Slides (Box C5)
  - Xanadune: St. Simon Sales Center, 1972
    - Manuscript Materials (Box C5)
    - Schematic/Design Development Drawings (Box C19, Box C49)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box C19)
    - Photographs (Box C5)
    - Slides (Box C5)
  - Yale Mathematics Building Competition, 1969-1970
    - Manuscript Materials (Box N1)
    - Presentation Drawings (Box N1)
  - Yurko House, 1972
    Job location: Morehead City, NC
    - Architectural/Structural Drawings (Box C43)
    - Mechanical/Electrical/HVAC Drawings (Box C43)
- Born digital records (Box J60–J70)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
  - River Design Dayton Program #1, 2010-M-049-0001; 1 (Box J60)
  - River Design Dayton Program #2, 2010-M-049-0002; 1 (Box J61)
  - River Design Dayton Program #3, 2010-M-049-0003; 1 (Box J62)
  - River Design Dayton Program #4, 2010-M-049-0004; 1 (Box J63)
  - River Design Dayton Program #5, 2010-M-049-0005; 1 (Box J64)
  - River Design Dayton Program #6, 2010-M-049-0006; 1 (Box J65)
  - FAC-TV May 18, 1984 Panel + Awards, 2010-M-049-0007; 1 (Box J66)
  - Watkins Glen Tomorrow 27/79, 2010-M-049-0008; 1 (Box J67)
  - Watkins Glen Tomorrow 11/17/79, 2010-M-049-0009; 1 (Box J68)
  - Watkins Glen Tomorrow 3/19/80, 2010-M-049-0010; 1 (Box J69)
  - Watkins Glen Tomorrow, 2010-M-049-0011; 1 (Box J70)